Let me ask you a question. What did you do yesterday?
让我问你一个问题 你昨天做了什么？
Did you go to the beach? Take a walk around the block?
你是去了海边 还是在街区散步？
Cook yourself some sweet and sour chicken because it's amazing?
或者做了一份味道超赞的菠萝咕噜鸡？
What about the day before yesterday?
那么前天呢？
How about two weeks ago?
两周前呢？
When I was young, my parents wanted me to keep
我小时候 父母鼓励我写日记
a daily journal so that I could look back on it
让我以后可以翻看日记
sometime in the future and remember places I'd gone and experiences I'd encountered.
从而想起我走过的地方和遇到的经历
Unfortunately, I wrote in it about once a year,
不幸的是 我差不多每年只写一篇
which is terrible because the entries weren't
这很糟糕 因为这些日记条目
detailed at all and just touched on high-level events.
一点也不详细 只记了些大而笼统的事件
A good journal entry should have a date so you know when it occurred,
一篇好的日记应该包含日期 让你知道具体的时间
a heading so you can give it a short description of that entry,
要有标题 让你可以添加一个简短的描述
and then the entry itself that has all of the information.
然后是包含所有信息的日记主体
Each time a new entry is made in the journal,
每次在日记上添加新的条目时
it's like making a commit in the repository.
就像在仓库中进行提交一样
And just like your journal entries,
而且就像日记条目一样
you want your commits to be frequent and
你的提交最好也能频繁和详细
descriptive so you can see the progress of your project over time.
让你可以看到项目逐步的进展情况
Git automatically records the date and
git 会自动记录
the content changes that have been made when a commit is created,
创建提交时的日期和所作的内容更改
so all you need to do is provide the descriptive heading or message for the commit.
所以你需要做的就是为提交提供详细的标题或说明
You want journal commits to be frequent so that you can
我们希望日记条目频繁一些
see the ups and downs in life over time.
以便了解不同时期的生活动态
Similarly, you want to make frequent commits with descriptive messages.
同样 你也希望提交频繁、说明详细
This will make it easy to look back at the project and see how it has evolved.
这样可以很容易地回顾这个项目 看看它是如何发展的
We're not making commits just yet,
我们先不实际进行提交
but start getting used to the idea that you should make
而是先来习惯这个概念 就是你应该
commits often with descriptive commit messages.
经常提交 并提供详细的提交说明
But how often is often,
但“经常”是多久一次？
and how can you know what makes a good commit?
你又怎么知道什么才是好的提交呢？
How many files or lines of code should be included in the commit?
应该在提交中包含多少文件或代码行？
One of the best ways to know what makes a good commit is to look at existing commits.
要想知道什么是好的提交 最好的方法之一就是查看现有的提交
The tools we'll be using to review a repository's history are git log and git show.
我们将用于查看仓库历史记录的工具是 git log 和 git show
With git log, you'll be able to display information about the existing commits.
使用 git log 你可以显示有关现有提交的信息
Git log is extremely powerful and you'll be using it all of the time.
git log 非常强大 你会经常用到它
The git show command displays info about the given commit.
git show 命令可以显示有关给定提交的信息
So, with this one, you provide it the commit ID,
对于这个命令 你需要向其提供提交 ID
also known as the SHA,
也被称为 SHA
and the command displays info about just that one commit.
该命令就会显示有关这一提交的信息
Just two commands, git log and git show.
这两个命令 git log 和 git show
Seem small, right? But this might actually be the most important lesson in the course.
不太起眼 对吧？但这可能是整个课程中最重要的一课
Learning how to display a repository's history and reviewing
学习如何显示仓库历史记录
specific commits is useful for so many things.
和查看特定的提交对各方面都很有用
Are you ready? You're focused?
准备好了吗？打起精神了吗？
Let's look at the all powerful git log.
让我们来看看功能强大的 git log